# Matthias Bachfischer

Munich, Germany

■ bachfischer.matthias@gmail.com | 🖸 Bachfischer | 🛅 Bachfischer

### Summary\_

Currently studying Data Science at The University of Melbourne - worked as an IT Architect at BCG Platinion prior to that. Strong technical background in statistics & machine learning as well as deep business expertise in digital transformation topics. I am interested in working on challenging problems with real-world impact.

#### Skills\_

**Programming Languages IT Certifications** 

**Software Frameworks** 

Proficient in Python, Java and R, Familiar with Go, JavaScript and C / C++

Certified SCRUM Master (PSM I), Certified Product Owner (PSPO I) Various ML frameworks (PyTorch, Tensorflow), Apache Hadoop

**Education** 

#### The University of Melbourne

M.Sc. IN DATA SCIENCE

Mar 2020 - Mar 2022

- · Learned advanced concepts in the area of statistics, probability and computer science
- Experimented with various frameworks and techniques for machine learning & deep learning
- Title of final thesis: An Investigation Into the Effectiveness of Learned Indexes under Adversarial Settings

#### Ostbayerische Technische Hochschule Regensburg

**B.Sc.** IN BUSINESS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Oct. 2014 - Feb. 2018

- · Learned various programming languages (Java, Javascript etc.), databases, computer networks and operating systems
- Evaluated the feasibility of using machine learning in intrusion detection systems
- Title of final thesis: Success Factors in Business-Managed IT

#### Universidad de Buenos Aires

LICENCIATURA EN ANÁLISIS DE SISTEMAS

Mar. 2016 - Jul. 2016

Semester abroad as an exchange student in the Faculty of Engineering (Facultad de Ingeniería)

#### Industrie- und Handelskammer Regensburg

IT SPECIALIST (SYSTEM INTEGRATION)

Jul. 2013 - Jan. 2017

· Professional training as part of the integrated degree program at KRONES AG

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_

### **BCG Platinion GmbH**

IT ARCHITECT & VISITING ASSOCIATE

Jul. 2018 - Mar. 2020

- Advised various companies from Industrial Goods & Automotive sector on digital transformation & IT strategy
- Designed, built, and implemented digital platforms and IT architectures using state-of-art technologies

#### King Abdullah University of Science and Technology

Apr. 2018 - Jul. 2018

VISITING STUDENT

**KRONES AG** 

- · Published a paper on using Machine Learning & Deep Learning techniques to classify toxic comments in online social networks
- · Worked on designing and implementing a dataset-driven search engine for scientific publications

INTEGRATED DEGREE PROGRAM - INFORMATION SYSTEMS

Jul. 2013 - Feb. 2018

• Implemented a big data platform based on Apache Hadoop

· Supported various business departments at KRONES with their software - and requirements engineering activities

**KRONES do Brasil** 

Aug. 2015 - Sept. 2015

· Performed the migration of a stand-alone e-mail system to centrally hosted system based on MS Exchange

• Trained the local IT staff to carry out IT support activities related to email and mobile device management

JULY 19, 2021

INTERNSHIP

MATTHIAS BACHFISCHER · CURRICULUM VITAE

#### **Honors & Awards**

2016 **Scholarship**, German Academic Scholarship Foundation

2020 **Study Abroad Scholarship**, German Academic Exchange Service

Bonn, Germany Bonn, Germany

### **Projects**\_

#### Implementation of a real-time data analytics platform for connected cars

• Design and implementation of a cloud-based real-time data analytics platform for a leading German automotive OEM to process and analyze streaming data from connected cars in real-time (AWS)

#### Design of a target IT architecture to enable analytics use cases in manufacturing

• Design of a target IT architecture to enable implementation of manufacturing analytics use cases for a large automotive supplier

### **Publications**

#### **Success Factors in Business-Managed IT**

Berlin, German

SKILL - STUDIERENDENKONFERENZ INFORMATIK

Sept. 2018

Presented a research paper from a case study analysis of critical success factors in Business-Managed IT (i.e. Shadow-IT systems that are operated overtly and with support of the IT organization)

#### Offensive Comment Classification on German Language Microposts

Vienna, Austria

GERMEVAL 2018 - SHARED TASK ON THE IDENTIFICATION OF OFFENSIVE LANGUAGE

Sept. 2018

 Presented the participation of the KAUST Laboratory for Machine Intelligence and kNowledge Engineering (MINE) at the GermEval 2018 shared task (research paper + poster)

## **Academic Experience**

#### Java Programming Lecture - Ostbayerische Technische Hochschule Regensburg

Reaensbura, German

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Oct. 2017 - Feb. 2018

- Teaching assistant for Java Programming lecture ("Programming 2")
- Responsible for weekly programming exercises with first-year students

### Languages\_

German, maternal languagenative speadEnglish, excellent commandLevel C2 (CESpanish, very good commandLevel C1 (CEPortuguese, good commandLevel B2 (CEArabic, working knowledgeLevel B1 (CEChinese, basic knowledgeLevel A1 (CE

## **Extracurricular Activity**

#### **International Negotiating Skills**

Regensburg, Germany

Additional Training

Oct. 2015 - Jul. 2017

· Lectures and seminars on theoretical frameworks for cross-cultural studies and advice on how to act in an international environment

#### Campus Asyl - Association to support refugees in Germany

egensburg, Germany Mar. 2017 - Aug. 2017

MENTO

• Mentoring and assistance for refugees studying for a university degree at OTH Regensburg

MATTHIAS BACHFISCHER · CURRICULUM VITAE